rotana.com 2009-03-25

# Rotana Hotels: Middle East Luxury Hotels: Luxury Hotels in Dubai, Abu Dhabi, Sharjah, Al Ain, Damascus, Hurghada & Sharm El Sheikh

|   
---  
|   | 

**Rotana. Online Privacy Statement  
  
Our Online Mission:**

At Rotana, we are dedicated to protecting your privacy and safeguarding your personally identifiable information. Rotana's mission is to consistently exceed our guests' expectations in terms of the products and services we provide to our business and leisure travelers. We strive to create an experience that is responsive to our guests' needs by using the information you entrust us with responsibly. Rotana is committed to respecting your privacy and adhering to the principles of applicable data protection and privacy laws throughout the world. 

We have provided this Privacy Statement as an explanation of the information we collect, how we use it, and how the use of this information can benefit your experience on our web sites and during your relationship with us. We wish to help you make informed decisions, so please take a moment to read the sections below.   
**  
THE WORLD OF ROTANA:**

In order to provide multiple access points to the services and products we offer, Rotana. operates directly, or through its affiliates or service providers, many web sites, including [www.almaharotana.com](http://www.almaharotana.com/), [www.alrawdarotana.com](http://www.alrawdarotana.com/), [www.beachrotana.com](http://www.beachrotana.com/), [www.alainrotana.com](http://www.alainrotana.com/), [www.gefinorrotana.com](http://www.gefinorrotana.com/), [www.hazmiehrotana.com](http://www.hazmiehrotana.com/), [www.queencenterrotana.com](http://www.queencenterrotana.com/), [www.albustanrotanahoteldubai.com](http://www.albustanrotanahoteldubai.com/), [www.almuroojrotanahoteldubai.com](http://www.almuroojrotanahoteldubai.com/), [www.jumeirarotana.com](http://www.jumeirarotana.com/), [www.rihabrotana.com](http://www.rihabrotana.com/), [www.rimalrotana.com](http://www.rimalrotana.com/), [www.towerrotana.com](http://www.towerrotana.com/), [www.villarotanahoteldubai.com](http://www.villarotanahoteldubai.com/), [www.coralbeachrotanaresorthurghada.com](http://www.coralbeachrotanaresorthurghada.com/), [www.coralbeachrotanaresortsarmelsheikh.com](http://www.coralbeachrotanaresortsarmelsheikh.com/), [www.sharjahrotana.com](http://www.sharjahrotana.com/), [www.coralbeachrotanaresorttiran.com](http://www.coralbeachrotanaresorttiran.com/), [www.grandrotanaresortsharmelsheikh.com](http://www.grandrotanaresortsharmelsheikh.com/) . Any one of these web sites may ask for and collect personally identifiable information in order to enhance your experience and provide you with relevant information.   
**  
TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT:**

Rotana collects information about our guests and visitors to our web sites so that we can provide an experience that is responsive to our guests' and visitors' needs. Information may be collected as part of: (i) fulfilling reservation or information requests, (ii) purchasing products, (iii) registering for program membership, (iv) submitting a job application, or (v) responding to communications from us (e.g., surveys, promotional offers, or reservation confirmations). We endeavor to collect information only with your knowledge and with your permission if necessary. The types of personally identifiable information that we collect may include your name, home, work and e-mail addresses, telephone and fax numbers, credit card information, date of birth, gender, and lifestyle information such as room preferences, leisure activities, names and ages of children, and other information necessary to fulfill special requests (e.g., health conditions that require special room accommodations).   
Rotana may also collect non-personally identifiable information about you, such as your use of our web sites, communication preferences, travel habits, aggregated data relative to your stays, and responses to promotional offers and surveys.   
**  
PURPOSE FOR COLLECTION, PROCESSING, AND DISCLOSURE:**  
 **  
Collection & Use: **

Rotana is fully committed to providing you with information about the collection and use of personally identifiable information (PII) furnished by, or collected from, visitors while using our web sites, products and services. It is our practice not to ask you for information unless we need it or intend to use it. Some of the primary purposes for collecting your PII are as follows:

  * providing services such as processing a transaction (e.g., making a reservation, fulfilling a request for information, or completing a product order) 
  * marketing and communications with you in relation to the products and services offered by Rotana, our strategic marketing partners, and other trusted third parties 
  * performing market research via surveys to better serve your needs, improve the effectiveness of our web sites, your hotel experience, our various types of communications, advertising campaigns, and/or promotional activities 

You will always be offered the choice not to submit your PII or to decide what communications you want to receive from us. However, doing so may cause certain transactions to become affected. For example, not providing a name will prevent the processing of reservations.   
**  
Processing and Disclosure:  
**  
In most cases, the information you provide is added to a local or global database. In the course of processing your information, it may be necessary to transfer your PII to Rotana's affiliates, properties within the Rotana system and/or third party service providers located in the United States and throughout the world for the purposes outlined within this Privacy Statement. As a general practice, Rotana does not sell, rent, or give physical possession of your PII to unaffiliated third parties outside the Rotana system. Situations in which Rotana may disclose your information to others include:

  * When we have received your consent to do so 
  * In situations where sharing or disclosing your information is required in order to offer you products or services you desire (e.g., a vacation package) 
  * When companies or services providers that perform business activities on behalf of Rotana require such information (e.g., credit card processing, customer support services, market research administration or database management services) 
  * When a property leaves the Rotana system and access to your PII is necessary to facilitate business operations or meet contractual obligations 
  * In the event Rotana is merged or acquired by another company 
  * To comply with legal or regulatory requirements or obligations in accordance with applicable law or court order 
  * In case of emergency such as to safeguard the life, health, or property of an individual 

If information is shared as mentioned above, we seek to limit the scope of information that is furnished to the amount necessary for the performance of the specific function. Unless otherwise precluded by legal process, we require third parties to protect your PII and abide by applicable privacy laws and regulations.   
**  
CONSENT:**

As part of our commitment to keep you informed, we may mail, e-mail, telephone, or contact you by other means to notify you of new Rotana Hotels products and services, or upcoming Rotana Hotels special offers, events, enhancements, or other relevant information that may be of interest to you. You may also receive mailings or other communications from carefully selected third parties. We always offer you the option to decline any or all of these communications by following the directions included in our e-mails or other communications, or by contacting Rotana directly. 

If you are a Rotana Preferred Guest (Rotana Reward) program member, you may also change your communication choices by updating your e-mail preferences in your individual membership profile.   
We would like to keep all of our guests and visitors informed and equally able to take advantage of the benefits offered by Rotana and its strategic marketing partners. However, if you reside outside of the United States, certain data privacy regulations may require us to obtain your permission before we send you information that you have not requested from us. 

In some cases your permission will be implied from the nature of the service requested or transaction undertaken. For example, Rotana may collect and use personally identifiable information that you volunteer, or behavioral data or information collected in the aggregate. In addition, your permission will be deemed given for communications from us that are necessary to fulfill transactions and services that you request. 

In certain circumstances, we will seek your express permission when we collect information that is regarded under certain data privacy regulations to be sensitive in nature (e.g., information revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, or health conditions).   
**  
ON-LINE TECHNOLOGIES:**

Rotana may use cookies, invisible pixels, and web beacons to obtain information about you while visiting our web sites. A cookie is a very small text file that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. It assigns the computer with a unique identifier, which in turn, becomes your identification card whenever you return to a Rotana Hotels web site.   
Cookies are designed to save you time because they help us to provide you with a customized experience without you having to remind us of your preferences each time you return to our web pages. Rotana cookies are not designed to damage your files, nor can they read information from other files on your computer hard drive.   
Cookies can also help us provide you with a personalized on-line experience in the following ways:

  * They remember your user name and password for future visits so log-in is easier and faster 
  * They ensure you are provided with the appropriate frames and content 
  * They ensure you obtain all requested information 
  * They help us deliver communications that are relevant and responsive to your interests and location   

Rotana cookies are limited to our web sites only, and are not designed to follow you when traveling on the Internet after leaving Rotana owned web sites. We track the usage of our web sites in order to better meet your needs and to help make it easier for you to find information in the future. Please note that in addition to Rotana cookies, various third parties may also place cookies on your computer's hard drive. Rotana is not responsible for the presence or absence of third party cookies, or for the technological capabilities or practices employed by third parties in connection with third party cookies. 

If you would prefer not to have the benefits of cookies, your Internet browser can be adjusted to treat cookies in different ways. Depending upon the type of browser you are using, you may be able to configure your browser so that: (i) you are prompted to accept or reject cookies on an individual basis or (ii) you may be able to prevent your browser from accepting any cookies at all. You should refer to the supplier or manufacturer of your web browser for specific details about cookie security. However, you should also understand that rejecting cookies might affect your ability to perform certain transactions on our web sites and our ability to recognize your browser from one visit to the next. 

Rotana also uses invisible pixels, sometimes called web beacons, to count how many people visit certain web pages. Information collected from invisible pixels is used and reported in the aggregate and does not contain personally identifiable information. Rotana Hotels may use this information to improve marketing programs and content.   
**  
LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES:**

In order to anticipate your needs, Rotana provides links to other web sites for your convenience and information. Rotana is not responsible or liable for any content presented by or contained on any independent web site, including, but not limited to, any advertising claims or marketing practices. Please note that while Rotana will protect your information on Rotana owned and operated web sites, we cannot control and will not be responsible for the privacy policies of third party web sites, including web sites owned or controlled by independent franchisees, third party owners of hotel, resort, interval ownership, or residence properties that may use the name of a Rotana brand, or web sites not controlled or authorized by Rotana. Third party web sites that are accessed through links on our web sites have separate privacy and data collection practices, and security measures. We have no responsibility or liability for the practices, policies and security measures implemented by third parties on their web sites. We encourage you to contact them to ask questions about their privacy practices, policies and security measures before disclosing any personally identifiable information. We recommend that you review the privacy statements and policies of linked web sites to understand how those web sites collect, use and store information.   
**  
MINORS:**

Rotana does not seek to obtain nor does it wish to receive personally identifiable information directly from minors; however, we cannot always determine the age of persons who access and use our web sites. If a minor (as defined by applicable law) provides us with his/her data without parental or guardian consent, we encourage the parent or guardian to contact us to have this information removed and to unsubscribe the minor from future Rotana Hotels marketing communications.   
**  
UPDATES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT:**

Rotana may amend this Privacy Statement from time to time in order to meet changes in the regulatory environment, business needs, or to satisfy the needs of our guests, properties, strategic marketing partners, and service providers. Updated versions will be posted to our web site and date stamped so that you are always aware of when the Privacy Statement was last updated.

|  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---  
|  | Privacy Statement |  | Site Map |  | Terms & Conditions  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
|  | This is Rotana | | |  | [Centro by Rotana](http://www.centrobyrotana.com/) | | |  | Alliances | | |  | Industry Partners | | |  | Press Room | | |  | Image Library | | |  | [Careers](http://rotanacareers.com/) | | |  | Contacts | | |  | Hotels & Spa Directory | | |  | Meeting & Events Directory | | |  | Dining & Entertainment | | |  | Our Destinations | | |  | Rewards  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---
